well hello internet and welcome to my
Kotlin video tutorial in this one
tutorial I'm going to cover pretty much
what you would find in a standard 250
300 page book on cotton 1 which means
the core syntax of the entire language
and like always in the description
underneath the video is a link to all of
the code from this video as well as
timestamps to all the individual parts
of the video so you can watch whatever
you want or watch part of the video and
come back to it or do whatever and also
I'm going to show you how to install
everything you're going to need to
complete this video and I have a lot to
do so let's get into it alright I'm
guessing you already have the Java
development kit installed if you do not
then you're going to have to go just
type in Java development kit don't worry
about this and you're going to come to a
page it looks like this and you're going
to find whatever operating system you
are using Linux Mac OS windows whatever
click on that and install that stuff and
I'm going to go pretty quickly here then
you're going to need to go to JetBrains
comm IDE 8 and download and more
specifically whether you're on Windows
or Mac OS we're going to be using the
free community version so you're going
to click on download and if you're on
Mac OS you're going to see this little
guy pop up down here dmg click on open
and then you're going to the folder that
opens you're going to grab the IntelliJ
application and drop it in your
Applications folder and then whenever
you do that this guy's going to open up
you're going to decide if you want a
white interface or a dark interface
click on keymaps and click on I've never
used IDE a and click on launch or script
checkmark inside of here and click on
default plugins and all this is fine
just click on featured plugins all
that's fine click on start using
IntelliJ then to create your very first
cutland project whenever this guy opens
up click on create new project come over
here on the left side of the screen
click on Kotlin and click on Kotlin JVM
and click on next this guy is going to
pop up here give your project a name I
called mine Kotlin tuts
it's this is automatically going to open
up like this you're going to click on
project SDK and you're going to click on
this guy and go and find whatever JVM
you want to use come down here click on
finish whatever you do this is going to
open up you're going to come over to
your source directory right click on it
click on new and then Kotlin file class
this guy's going to pop up inside of
here give it a name I called nine Kotlin
tub again call it whatever you want
click on OK and then you're going to
type the simple hello world script
inside here just to verify everything
works type exactly what you see there
and you can click on pause we want to
check that out and whenever you do hello
world is going to print down here you're
probably more than likely going to see
this it's a bug
don't worry about it it's your
applications are going to compile
perfectly fine it's just a known bug
that will go away finally or eventually
and that's how you install both IntelliJ
and Kotlin on a Mac o west computer and
now I'll show you how to set it up on
Windows basically the same thing alright
so you go to JetBrains comm ide a
download you're going to come over here
click on Windows then I'm going to click
on download then this guy is going to
pop up down here you're going to click
on save this is going to pop up and
you're going to click on next and this
is perfectly fine click on next and
leave everything the way it is click on
next and it is going to install
everything for you after it's all done
installing you're going to see this guy
leave this run IntelliJ Community
Edition checked and click on finish and
what we're going to do here is do not
import settings and click on OK and then
you're going to check if you want a
white or a black interface click on
default plugins leave everything the
same featured plug-in start using
IntelliJ click on that guy come in here
create a new project you're going to
come in and click on Kotlin Kotlin JVM
come down here click on next come back
up inside of here you're going to click
on give your project a name you're going
to click inside of here to select the
SDK you want to use and you can see
right there I use version 1.8 and then
I'm going to click on finish this is
going to open up you're going to come
over to source right click on it to
click on new and Kotlin file class
you're going to type in exactly what I
typed in for I'll show you that here in
a second oh by the way if you want to
run and your code you're going to click
on run and run and that's kind of run it
for you and whenever you click on run in
Windows it's going to come up like this
so you're going to click on demo Kotlin
Tots or whatever you call doors click on
that by the way here is the simple hello
world application I'm going to use to
verify that everything is installed
properly and after you run it you're
going to see down here that hole
world prints out all right so now you
have Kotlin and IntelliJ and all that
stuff installed now let's start writing
some code all right so this should all
look familiar because that's exactly
what you have here oh by the way
everybody always asked me how did I get
this from the bottom to the right you're
going to right-click on it like that and
you're going to click on move to your
go-to top left bottom or right okay so
that's how I did that
all right so let's write some code first
thing I want to talk about are variables
by the way this is where all your
application is your main function this
is where everything is going to execute
and then right here you can see is how
you print out to screen very first I'm
going to talk about our variables now
there are different types of variables
there are mutable and immutable and
immutable sometimes referred to as
read-only variables and you create an
immutable or an unchangeable variable by
typing in Val and then let's say name is
equal to Derek okay there you go
you just created yourself a read only
variable you can also create mutable
variables inside of Kotlin by changing
Val into variable and I'll say something
like my age is equal to 42 okay my name
hopefully is never going to change and
my age more than likely will so that is
the difference between those two guys
now Kotlin uses what is called type
inference so whenever I put a string
inside of here Kotlin knows that this is
a string and it refers to it as a string
likewise here it's going to refer to my
age as an integer and those squiggly
lines are there because I'm you can see
right here variable my age is never used
all right IntelliJ is a very verbose
with warnings so what I want to do here
is even though it will figure out what
the type is on its own you can also come
in and define your type so let's say I
want to come in here and I want to
create a mutable or changeable variable
I'm going to call this big int and I
want this to be an integer well you may
ask yourself well how big of an integer
can I store inside of there
well I can go and call max value and it
will tell me exactly that and we're
going to find out what that is and then
we can go and tell this small intz like
that and I will just change this to
in value and I'll be able to get that
value as well I can then come in and go
print line and I'll say something like
biggest int and we can go and put the
information in here and multiple
different ways one thing we can do is
just put a plus sign inside of there and
then put big int like that or we could
also come in and we could say small list
means small list int and this is
obviously going to be big in but I'm
gonna get rid of that all together and
I'm gonna put that guy right there and
you can use what it's called string
interpolation which is going to allow me
to put small int inside of there and how
I do that is I come in and I put a
dollar sign followed by whatever the
name is for my variable and you can see
it gives you all sorts of different
information here all right so we got
that all set up and if I want to run it
come in and run it and it's going to
print all of that out and here you can
see the biggest integer I can have is
that big number and the smallest integer
is that number and there's two different
ways to place that information or print
that information out on my screen don't
worry about all of the warnings they're
just telling me I'm not using this in
that all right let's get rid of that so
that warnings go away now there are of
course many other different variable
types
you're going to have integers which are
referred to using int you are also going
to have Long's and here in a second I
will show you how big or how small along
can be you're going to have doubles
you're also going to have floats you're
also going to have volumes boolean and
as per numbers you can have shorts which
are going to be 16 bytes or you can have
bytes which are going to be 8 bytes and
let's go in here and oh well so you'll
have characters I'm going to show you
examples of all these different guys
though all right all right so I went in
here I already showed you I typed in the
how to find out the biggest int and the
smallest int I then went in and created
the largest long and the smallest long
the largest doubles and so forth and so
on and floats and all that fun stuff
we're going to run it and you're going
to say over here on the right side of
the screen all of that look how big
Long's are these are
all right and there is the biggest
double and the smallest and all of those
different things now one thing that is
important to be aware of however is
there is a loss of precision whenever
you are working with floating-point
numbers and let me go and give you an
example of what I mean by that let's go
and create a variable and double num1
and this is going to be a double is
equal to and I'm going to go 1 and what
you're going to do here is you're going
to with your doubles you're going to
have a precision up to 15 digits so even
though they can be gigantic they're
really not so what you want to be aware
of is I'm going to go okay so there is
15 digits let's add 16 on there and then
we're going to come in here and we're
going to copy that paste that inside of
there change this to double num2 and
then I'm going to print out the
difference or the sum let's do a sum and
then you'll be able to see how it fails
up fails whenever I'm working with it so
you can also come in here go plus sign
like this and you could go and perform
your arithmetic directly inside of here
double Nam 1 and double num2 like that
no you probably have noticed there are
no semicolons inside of Kotlin let's run
that and you're going to see that
everything added up perfectly fine a
whole bunch of ones until it got right
here to the sixteenth digit and it
messed up so just want to make you aware
that precision falls apart after 15
digits of course you should always
verify that on your own computer though
now to take a look at bouillon bouillon
can either have a value of true or false
that is it let's go into a real simple
example so I'm going to say if true and
what you can do here is you can use the
phrase or keyword is to see if a
variable is a integer or a double or a
float or a boolean and that's what I'm
doing right here so I'm saying is true a
boolean yes I can do that and then I can
command you can also come in here and
put print like this and go true is
boolean and then what this is going to
do is print out the screen but not add a
new line but you can go in here and put
a new line in there for yourself and do
that and it's going to come back as true
true is bullying all right good stuff
and let's do one more example here with
variables before I get into casting a
couple other a lot of other things let's
go and create a character how we do that
is let's say something like letter grade
and we go character like this is equal
to a character is going to be surrounded
with single digits and there you go
there is a character and I could come in
here just to verify that this indeed is
a character by saying a is a and
character whoops
spell character right there we are and
we can come in and go a plus and
actually you do something else I can go
and put form this without using that
plus sign I can go a dollar sign and put
two curly brackets in there and then I
can go letter grade is a character and
that is all legit and we can run it and
you can see that indeed it's going to
come back a as a character and true is
indeed true so that is how another way
we can use string interpolation and I
want to show you briefly how casting
works now if you want to cast from one
value in another let's go and just get
rid of that all together right there you
can it's quite easy so let's paste this
in here and let's just change what this
is so let's say we wanted to go 3.14 two
and integer so we can cast from a double
to an integer well I could then come in
and go 3.14 if you want to cast a double
or a float to an integer
you just put a dot and two int followed
by parentheses and it is automatically
going to do this where it looks forgot
to put the plus sign all right so
there's that that's how we can convert
from a double to an integer and let's go
and convert from a letter grade just to
so something weird it works with any of
them so just go in there and play around
on your own and you'll see so let's
convert an A into an integer see how
that works out
so I'm going to go letter grade that
I've deleted the letter grade yeah so
let's just get rid of it and we'll just
go I can put put it directly inside here
surrounded with single quotes and then
go to ends Kotlin doesn't care
all that's cool and then we command and
I'm going to do it the next one oh well
we can get that value right there we'll
say 65 to character and see what that
works out to be so we'll put 65 inside
out of there and we'll say to character
like that and we can run all those guys
and you can see that all of those work
and that's how casting works inside of
caught one and now I'm going to jump
over and show you a whole bunch of
different things we can do with strings
alright
so strings are just double quoted series
of characters and of course we put Val
inside of there what does that mean that
means that's a value that is not going
to change and we can go and put my name
inside of there I can remember how to
spell it there we are so there we are we
just created a string and let's go and
create a long string so we'll go long
string you can also come in here and put
double quotes again we're going to put
three of them and this is going to allow
me to let's put something different
inside out this is a come down here and
then I can go long string and then it
won't edit that at all it allows me to
do multi-line strings or whatever you'd
like let's go and create a couple more
here first name is equal to and I could
also come in here like this and go
string and define if I didn't want it to
go in there and infer what I'm doing
either way it works out so it'll go Doug
and let's just copy this guy right there
and come down here and let's go L name
and this will be Doug Smith of course
we're going to be able to come in here
and join these together actually you can
also change the value remember bow you
don't change var are you can let's
change it so I can just come in and go F
name is equal to Sally
alright so we were able to change that
value and let's say we wanted to go in
and join these strings together of
course we could do that we can just go F
name plus angle a so like that's and L
name and there we go that's how we go
and join our values together whoops
change
- an uppercase there we are alright so
that's how we can join strings like I
said before we're going to be able to
use string interpolation or just putting
a variable value directly inside of a
string that we plan on printing out so
we can go name like that and we can go
full name like that and that's going to
print that guy out it's going to do a
whole bunch more of these guys you're
going to like I said before you're going
to be able to print out I never know
when you guys are using time stamps and
jump around and doing whatever so I'm
going to cover this again it also to
come in here like this with a dollar
sign and curly brackets and perform
arithmetic operations directly inside of
your string you want to print out and
that all works good you're going to be
able to get your string length let's go
and just copy this guy right here paste
that inside of there and I will have all
this stuff whoops
keep this like this so I'm gonna go
string length and then if I want to get
to that said string length I know let's
do it for the long string I could do so
like this and then follow it up with the
word length what else can we do I can
compare strings so I could create two
brand-new strings here if I would like
or I could just compared ugh and Wow
let's do something a little different
there we go so I have two strings if I'm
never moving too quick just hit the
pause button I like to make videos in
which we use the pause button alright so
the only difference between string one
and string two is an uppercase a so
let's compare these to see how they work
out so pitch that in there and we're
going to change this up a little bit
let's say we want to go strings equal
and see if those strings are equal or
not how we can do a comparison between
these two guys is we can go string 1 +
equals and throw string 2 inside of
there and that's one way to set that off
also going to be able to compare another
one let's go and do a different thing
here and this is going to be a
comparison that is going to instead of
giving us true or false it's actually
going to give us a 0 in the situation
which the string is equal if it is
negative it's going to be a value that's
less
than zero if it's a positive it's going
to be greater than zero
so what we can do here is let's do a
slight compare let's go to compare a to
B and we can come in and like this and
we can just come in throw the a inside
of there like that and we'll use
compared to here instead of equals so
compared to and we'll throw B inside
here just to see how that works out for
us you can see we can put our double
quotes inside of here without having to
back slash them or anything and
everything works out perfectly fine and
let's run that just to see what all of
that stuff is and you can see right here
comparison A to B is negative one right
here you can see even though the only
difference is capital a that comes back
as false string length and you can see
how I added all that stuff together and
all of that other stuff so pretty neat
stuff let's go in and do a couple more
of these just get rid of that let's say
I would like to get a character at a
specific index I could do that as well
so let's say I want to get the seconds
index and I want to do that for string
one just leave string 1 be right there
and let's just change this to get and
then we'll come in here and we'll change
that to two that's going to get whatever
value is assigned to the second index
and this is giving me a little squiggle
saying that I don't have to do it this
way I could also come in here and do it
this way and you could do it either way
you wanted to do it it's completely up
to you I can also come in and get a
substring by providing where I want to
start and ending where I want to end up
to so it's come here I'll show you an
example so we'll come in here and let's
say I want to go and get index 2 through
7 how would I do that well let's do this
with string 1 once again let's go get
rid of all this and let me go sub
sequence and if I want to get from index
2 to 7 what I have to do is put 2 to 8
okay it goes up to index 8 but it
doesn't include it with the results and
then let's as a final little foot way of
working with strings let's say I want to
check to see if a string contains
another string and of course I can do
that
annals
say I want to check to see if it has the
value of random somewhere inside of it
so I can say something like contains
random and to check that I can get
string 1 and contains and then inside of
this guy I can put in whatever I want to
search for so random yeah that's right
and you can see over here on the right
side index 1 through 7 gets me random so
we go 0 1 2 say and that's how it gets
random contains random comes back is
true what is the second index is our why
is that well that's because it's a zero
index this is one index and whoops and
that's the second index so now it isn't
but now it is alright so good alright so
there's a rough overview of course there
are other functions available with
manipulating with strings inside of
Kotlin but those are the main guys and
now I want to talk about arrays okay so
Rays are going to be able to store
multiple values of multiple different
types and how we create one is go VAR
and we can go let's call this my array
is equal to and how we create an array
as you go array of let's say I want to
go one and one point two three and Doug
okay so you can see we can put multiple
different data types inside of here
you're going to be able to access these
guys just like you did anything else by
going my array like this and let's say
you want to get whatever is in the
second index that's how you do that you
can also change the value in a very
simple way let's say I want to change
whatever is in the first index just do
it like that and go equal to 3.14
whatever you want you can find out
easily how many elements are in your
array let's command
and let's go something like array length
and to get whatever that is you just go
my array and this time we're going to
use size and that'll give us a array
size and we can check if an element is
inside of an array so let's say we want
to verify that Doug is in right the
array that we have we can do that just
go my array and then we're going to go
contains and we're specifically looking
for Doug and that's going to come back
to or false if that's in there we're
also going to be able to get a number of
elements in an array and have it
returned as an array so we're going to
go bar like this I'm going to say call
this part array because it's part of
that array and I can go my array and
follow that up with copy of range and if
I want to get the first two elements
inside of the array then I'm pulling
information from I go 0 & 1 and of
course you increment that if you want
more of it we can then get the first
elements out of our array easily by just
let's just change this first and we can
then go string like that and then type
in first oops
first so that's going to give us our
first element and we can you could also
type in last if you want to get the last
element or whatever you'd like you could
also get the index of a value so let's
say I wanted to find out what is the
first index for Doug where that shows up
string 1 once again and here I'm going
to go index of and I'm gonna type in dog
and there's Doug and let's run that just
see what all this stuff does whoops I
messed that up whenever I try to do that
whoops let's change it back
oh all right now it looks okay so let's
say that and let's run it again oops I
typed in string 1 instead of my array
gonna fix that real quick my array and
my row run it and there you can see Doug
comes back where is that coming from
that's coming from right here where we
said we wanted whatever is in the second
index
array length you can see comes back as
three you can see the very first value
stored in the array is one and you can
see Doug index starts at the second
index inside of our rack alright so a
whole bunch of different things there
another thing that's really cool and I'm
going to show you how to do all kinds of
things with what are called collections
and array sort of be in one of these
collections let's say I'd like to create
an array of squares how hard would that
be well I can go more let's call this
square array is equal to I can call
array and five which is the total number
of indexes I want inside of there and
then what I want to do is I want to go
through one through five and have the
values multiplied times each other
sounds hard
not really I'm just going to type in X
and x times X so for each of the index
value is what it's going to do is it's
going to multiply whatever the index is
times itself you can see here in a
second exactly what that looks like now
let's just go and print that print line
like this and we go square array and -
alright so and we'll run that and you
see it comes back is for y well because
that second index is multiplied times
itself so it's the second one comes in
here two times two is equal to four so
that just created an array full of
squares so you could throw anything in
there you want I just used five but of
course you can do anything and one thing
I forgot to mention is of course there
are type specific arrays which means if
you want to have an array that can only
have one data type of course you can so
you just go like this and array like
this and integer and then if somebody
tries to store something inside of this
array that is not an integer it's going
to throw an error there so you go array
of and one two and three and of course
that is going to work out the way that
you would like it to alright so I'm
going to do more with arrays as the two
door continues but now I want to take a
pause here and take a look at ranges all
right so ranges are really cool what
they're basically and allow you to do is
to define basically a starting and an
ending value and do
all sorts of nifty little calculations
in between so let's say I want to create
a range that goes from one to ten how
would I do it I just do that and then I
go 1 dot dot 10 there it is
automatically generated it for me
likewise I can come in here and have it
work with letters so let's just call
this alpha is equal to and I'm going to
go double quotes here a dot dot and then
I want to throw a Z inside of there so
there we go we just created lists
automatically generating those for us
you're also going to be able to use in
to search a range so let's come in and
let's say that we want to search to find
out if r is inside of alpha we can do so
so we'll say something like R in alpha
and then we come in here get rid of all
this stuff and then we will go our in
whoops make sure you have that there in
an alpha and it will tell us if it's if
the R is stored inside of that range or
not we're also going to be able to
create ranges that would decrement
downwards so let's say we wanted to go
from 10 to 1 we could do so we go 10 to
1 and then we could go 10 and down to
and then whatever we want the last thing
to be we could create an array up to a
value so let's just go to to say we want
to go 20 is equal to and then we can go
to dot and in this situation we would
say range to 20 and what else can we do
we could step through an array so let's
say each value inside of our range I
means we can step through a range so say
we wanted to step through adding 3 each
time starting at the first value we
could do so let's go bow and let's call
this range 3 is equal to and then we can
go 1 to 10 and let's say we want to step
through adding 3 each time we can go
step and 3 not 2 of course and what else
can we do we can of course cycle through
a range and print information out we can
do the same thing
with arrays as you're going to see later
on or you can go back and test this out
so I can go for X N and we go range
three or we could do this with any of
the other ones and we go print a line
and what I'm going to do here is just so
we can tell what this is I'm going to go
range three and then we can go X and
that's going to print out all those
different values and of course the final
thing is we would be able to reverse a
range let's use the for loop again so
I'm going to go for X in and we'll go
ten to one and reverse and put that
there like that and then we'll just
print the information out again so we'll
go print line and reverse and X and that
is going to allow us to do all that we
will run it and you're going to see did
it work
what I have little bug 23 does it to do
oh this is reversed sorry about that I
remembered it wrong and let's run it
again and you can see everything here so
what we were able to do here with what
it says is are in alpha remember we use
the keyword in to check if the letter R
is in this range and indeed it comes
back it's true you can see we came down
here and we went and added three to each
of these values and then printed them
out on the screen using this flow for
loop here you can see 1 plus 3 is equal
to 4 plus 3 is equal to 7 and so forth
and so on and then we also came here and
use 10 to 1 and we re reversed it and
that's reason why we have 1 through 10
all right so a whole bunch of cool
things we can do with ranges more is
coming as this tutorial continues and
now I want to talk about conditionals
all right so of course there's going to
be a bunch of different conditional
operators I'm going to show you here and
you're going to have greater than you're
going to have less than you're going to
have greater than or equal to you're
going to have less than or equal to
you're going to have equal to and you're
going to have not equal to you're also
going to have logical operators and like
I said I'm going to show you all these
you're going to and you're going to have
or and you're going to have not all
right so I'll show you a couple examples
how they work using if and else if and
else so let's say we go and create a
value here remember this is in immutable
it's not going to change
so we're going to vow age in this
situation age will not change so I'm
gonna say if age is less than five in
that situation what we're going to do is
print line and we'll say something like
go to preschool maybe a little bit early
to send a infants preschool but it's
going to work in our world and then
you're going to be able to go else if
there's no LF for any of that crazy
stuff inside of Kotlin we can say age is
equal to five and in that situation
we're going to say that you can go to
kindergarten and there's kindergarten
and else is and now we can stack these
using logical operators so we could go
and say something like let's put two
parentheses in there if age is greater
than five and meaning that both sides of
this conditional operator has to be true
for this to come back with the value of
true and if a is less than or equal to
seventeen in that situation I'm going to
say that we're going to calculate the
grade that the student is going to be
working or going to and we'll do that by
taking age minus five and remember no
semicolons and then I will come in and
go print line and I'll say go to and
change this to grade and then use string
interpolation to throw grade inside of
there and then finally we can say else
which is going to be the default and in
that situation we'll say everybody else
can go to college and there you are
that's how if and else if and
conditional operators and logical
operators work why don't we see how work
if we're using what is called win which
works like switch in other languages win
is very cool here I'll run it for you
just you can see what the results are
ran it go to Grade three okay so you can
see it fell into this quadrant right
here subtracted five from the age and
that's the reason why so it's grade
three now let's take a look at the win
loo earth conditional operator and we'll
go win age I'm going to show you a bunch
of different things we can do here so we
go win age and then we'll say let's say
we wanted to match a list I know you
normally wouldn't do this but I'm going
to do it just show you this because
sometimes will work you can just go zero
and two and three and four and then come
out here put the little arrow in there
and go print line and say go to
preschool let's keep that the same
you're also going to be able to match a
specific value so we just go five like
that of course that's going to work for
you and air will say go to kindergarten
kindergarten and there that is we can
also match a range and we use in with
this so we'll say 6.17 and put an arrow
inside of there and here just put our
curly brackets and we can do all sorts
of other things so we can say grade is
equal to age minus five and then we can
print out that
so we'll say go to grade and we will
throw in whatever the grade is so
there's grade and then likewise you can
have a default value and that is else
also else and then we'll print this out
and say go to college all right so
that's if else if and else as well as
how to use when to do pretty much
exactly the same thing in numerous
different they this is really cool I
love win and you can see it gets exactly
the same results alright so there is a
rundown of some conditional operators
and conditional things we can do and now
I want to talk about looping alright so
basically of course you know looping is
going to allow us to cycle through
arrays and ranges or collections and all
sorts of other different things and
basically anything that implements an
iterator function so I already talked
about for loops a little bit let's do
another one so I'm going to go for X in
and here we're going to use a range I'm
going to go one dot dot ten and it's
going to cycle through one through ten
as you're probably guessing let's print
that out and we'll say something like
Lube Lube
I don't know stickler for uppercase
letters and then I'll just go X all
right so there is how we can come in and
work with or basically cycle through a
range now I want to do something a
little bit neater and this is what I'm
going to do is I'm going to use a while
loop and it's going to guess random
numbers but you may be asking how do we
calculate a Rand
number well the neat thing about Kotlin
is basically if there is a library
inside of Java you're going to be able
to use it inside of Kotlin so we go
imports Java dot util dot random so
there's a library we use to import or to
calculate random values with Java and
automatically we're going to be able to
use it with Kotlin so pretty cool
someone come down here now and generate
a random value how you do that you go
Val and we call this R and is equal to
random and then go Val and I'm gonna
call this magic number is equal to R and
and next I'm going to work with integers
so I want to find a random value from 50
to 1 or from 1 to 50 I guess it's a
better way of saying that let's change
this to magic number lowercase and now
let's use our while loop course with
while loop like in almost every other
language you're going to have a value
you're going to increment or work with
that you're going to have outside or
define before the while loop so I'm
going to save our guess is equal to zero
and just have it figure out whatever the
datatype for that is and then I'm going
to go and generate my while loop so I'm
going to go while magic num is not equal
to the guess in that situation I'm going
to come in and go guess and there's a
shortcut way of adding one to a value
and I'm going to keep incrementing the
value of guess until it gets to the
point where it finds what it wants and
then in that situation I can then say
magic number was and we'll just sort
guests inside there all right let's run
these guys and you can see how that
works out and there it is it looped
through printed one through ten and
magic number in this situation was 19
let's run it again and now it's 15 run
it again now it's 34 and you can see
that the random number generator is
working and also the Bible it's working
another thing let's go and do another
while loop but so that I can talk about
continue and break now let's do this as
a for loop so let's go for and we'll say
X in and I'm going to go 1 2 20 and
then what I'm going to do is I'm going
to say if X modulus 2 is equal to 0
modulus is going to give us the
remainder of a division and what this is
used for is to check if a value is even
or odd so if it comes back X modulus 2
is equal to 0 that means it's an even
number in that situation what I want to
do is continue back to the top of the
loop and basically skip over all of the
even values so I'm going to go continue
like that then after we get out of that
continue basically just skips everything
else that comes afterwards and jumps
back up here and this guy up here this
for loop is going to increment for us
otherwise I want to come in and go print
line and I'm going to print out an odd
value so I'm going to put it like that
and I'm gonna go X is going to be what I
print out and let's say that I want to
jump out prematurely and if the value is
ever equal to 15 how I can do that is I
can say if X is equal to 15 in that
situation I want to break out of it and
that is how that's going to work if I
run that you're going to see that that
indeed works so it only printed out the
odd values and whenever it got the 15 it
jumped out of the loop even though this
was supposed to continue going and it
ended and that's how continue in break
work inside of caught ones keep doing
some more let's go and create ourselves
an array here and SLAR let's call this
array 3 and let's define this as an
integer array is equal to array o + 3 +
6 + 9 and what we're going to do here is
iterate for the indices of our array how
we can do that is go 4 and I n ray 3 and
indices and what it's going to do is
return the indices for each of the
individual parts of the array and then
we'll be able to go in here and print
line like that and let's say I want to
get multiples of 3 which is why stored
inside of there
this and Ray 3
and throw an eye in there so that's a
way to get all that out of there and
then the final thing is I want to output
not only the index but also the value
for each of the values inside of the
Ring I can go for and then put double
parentheses inside of there and I'm
going to say index and value is what I
want to work with I'm going to say in
array 3 with index parentheses once
again since that is indeed a function
and then I'm going to print this out and
would go bats and index and I'm going to
get to the index and that's coming from
this guy right there you're going to see
more examples of how where like they
would pull information this way and I
want the value also
alright so save that didn't have any
bugs that's going to print out real nice
on the screen and indeed you can see
here I went and printed out those values
inside of our array by referring to
their index and here I printed out the
index as well as the values alright so
there is a whole bunch of different
things about a looping and I want to
talk about functions ok so whenever
you're defining a function it's going to
start out with the word fun and then
it's going to have whatever the function
name is a list of parameters as well as
their data type as well as a return type
so I'm going to do an example so let's
say we create a function called add then
inside of parentheses I'm going to say
that it is going to receive a parameter
I want to refer to as number one I'm
going to say that this is an integer and
I'm going to have a number two let's say
that's also an integer then after that
I'm going to put a colon and say its
return type is an integer and there's a
bunch of different things we can do here
and here we're going to use go equal 2
num1 plus num2 there's the whole entire
function all in one place and of course
we're going to be able to call for it to
work so let's go 5 plus 4 is equal to
and we can say add and pass in a 5 and a
4 alright so there it is that is how we
can do that let's run it just to see
what it looks like and you can say 5
plus 4 is equal to 9
okay now one thing that is interesting
is that you actually do not need a
return type whenever you are working
with single line functions this is a
single line function what we have right
here so let's go and I'll show you
exactly what I mean by that Linc's copy
this and just change it to subtract just
so I can show you an example so throw
that inside of there change this to
subtract it's once again going to
receive a number and another number and
another thing well since I'm here I
might as well talk about it you can also
have default values so let's say we
wanted to have a default we could do
that just like this and let's have the
defaults be equal to 1 in that situation
you're going to be able to get rid of
this in here in that situation and it's
still going to work out perfectly fine
and let's go get this guy and paste it
in there just so you can see that I'm
not lying to you sometimes say 5 minus 4
is equal to would be an interesting
tutorial I basically just make up a
bunch of things and people think it's
true but that is not going on right now
I just want to make sure you're clear on
that
ok so 5 minus 4 is equal to 9 what
subtract oh I went and slept out there
all right so it'll change that right
there and 5 minus 4 is equal to 1 ok so
there is how to set default values and
also point out the fact that this is a
single line function you don't need a
return value but put it in there you
might as well alright another thing
you're also going to be able to use what
are called named parameters and what I
mean by that is you're going to be able
to refer to these even though they're
out of order so I'm going to come in I'm
just gonna paste this inside of here
like that and here I'm going to say 4
minus 5 is equal to and I'm going to
call subtract so so tracks and then
we'll go in and name the parameter so
I'm going to say I want to put num2
inside of here first give it a value of
5 and then i'm going to have num1 and of
course i'm going to give it a value of 4
that is perfectly fine you can do that
as well you may ask yourself well what
do i put inside of here if i don't have
a return value well you're going to put
unit not void so let's go and create a
function that doesn't return anything
let's
call it say hello and it is going to
receive a name which is going to be a
string datatype and it is going to
return nothing so we put a colon in
there and just put in units and then we
can go and put equal to print line and
then inside of here go hello and
whatever the name was that was passed
inside of there and we can call this guy
actually we don't need that right there
we can just go say hello and pass in
call I don't know
there we go so there's that and what
else can we do with functions there's a
whole bunch we can create a function
that is going to return two values and
there's a couple different ways of doing
that
let's go Val and well let's create a
function outside of here we'll come down
inside of here and this is going to
return two values so we're going to go
fun next two and this is going to
receive a number and then it is going to
return the next two in line so whoops to
do so we're going to put a colon inside
of here and go pair and it's going to
return an integer and then it's going to
return another integer and to do that we
can go return and pair and I'm going to
go numb whoops plus 1 and then num plus
look to okay so that's what that
function does for us let's go and call
it up inside of here and how you do that
is you go eval and the two things one
I'm going to have a variable called two
and another one called
three is equal to and I'm going to call
the next two function inside of here
well make sure you spell it right next
to we're going to pass one value inside
of there and then we can come in and
print this out just so that we know that
it indeed works so I'm going to say one
and then I'm going to go to and I'm
going to go three because we want nuts
and we're going to see what a whole
bunch of these different guys do for us
so four minus five where is that guy
from all that's from this guy right here
and then we have hello Paul that comes
out there and then here we were able to
get two values passed back
from one function so a whole bunch of
neat things but there are more and more
are coming
you're also going to be able to send a
variable number of parameters we're
going to create a function outside of
here again so when we go function and we
call this get some and if I'm going to
receive a variable number of values I'm
going to type in var arg like that and
then give it whatever name i want i'm
going to call it numbs in this situation
and then I'm going to say integer and
I'm going to say that this is going to
return an integer and then I'm going to
go var sum is equal to zero and I'm
going to cycle through all of these
values as if they are an array which
they are array so to do that I can use a
function called for each and that's a
way to cycle through arrays so I'm going
to go n and I can do for each of these
values I can go sum plus whoops equal to
n and that's going to cycle through
every value in the array that's passed
inside of there and add those to the
value of sum and then afterwards it is
going to return whatever the final value
of sum is and we come in here and call
this guy to execute let's just do a
print line here just to keep it simple
and I can go sum and then let's go and
call get some so I'm going to go get
some and 1 2 3 4 and a 5 and there it is
and as there it is and you can see the
sum comes back is 15 we're also going to
be able to come in and define function
literals so let's say we want to have
multiplied like this is equal to and
we'll have num1 inside of there and
that's going to be an integer and num2
and that's also going to be an integer
and then this guy is going to return
whatever num1 is times num2 so we just
go in here put that there and then 1
times num2 and there that guy is and
we'll be able to come in and print this
so let's just do 5 times 3 and then call
the function itself multiplied and 5
and three and that'll work and we could
also something else cool is we could
calculate a factorial with tail
recursion I'm just going to show you an
example of this I'm not going to get
into recursion and how that works you
probably understand it if you don't
understand recursion just leave a
comment below and I'll give you an
example all right so I just wanted to
cover this just to cover it so outside
of here actually I'm going to let's get
rid of this guy right there because we
already covered that and get some let's
just get rid of it all right so what I'm
going to do is when we go fun and I'm
going to calculate a factorial using
tail recursion so factorial X : oops
integer and I'm guessing you guys have
seen me cover recursion a million times
so it's just not going to talk about it
right now like I said if you guys let me
leave it for comment in the pen I'll
give you an example
so I'm going to go tail recursion fun
fact call this fact tail and it's going
to Y which is going to be an integer and
Z which is going to be another integer
and it's going to return an integer and
this is just a function that calls
itself until it ends and anytime you
have a situation in which you're doing
that you have to have an exit scenario
so we're going to have our exit scenario
be whenever Y is equal to zero in that
situation we're going to turn return Z
otherwise we are going to continue
having our function call itself so we'll
say return and we'll call factorial tail
and we'll go to y -1 and Y times 2 or Y
times Z and I guess I guess I should
talk about what exactly a factorial is a
factorial is just five let's say you
have factorial 5 you would go 5 times 4
times 3 times 2 times 1
ok that's the factorial so that's what
I'm doing here just decrementing that
and then after this after it finishes
all this stuff we will go and return
factorial tail and x + 1 so to save that
then we can jump up inside of here and
show you what that looks like whenever
we exit
- tits so we'll go print line and we
will do factorial 5 just because that's
their so that's the factorial symbol and
we will go fact and inside here throw in
the value of 5 so we'll save it and run
it and you'll see that the factorial of
5 is equal to 120 all right so neat
stuff and more and more and more stuff
with functions is coming now I want to
talk about higher order functions okay
so a higher order function is just going
to be a function it either accepts or
returns another function so let's just
go and create a whole bunch of examples
here make that all make sense so what I
want to do here is I want to use a
filter which is going to be a collection
operator to find even values in a range
and I'm going to do a whole bunch of the
different collection operators because I
really need so I'm going to go numb list
and define a range from 1 to 20 and I
want to use filter on this to just find
my evens so what I'm going to do is go
bow and even list is equal to and we'll
go numb list and follow that up with a
filter and I can put IT inside here
basically how the way this works is that
if a function has only one parameter you
don't have to declare it but you just
use I T instead and it'll just work so
here this is going to represent each of
these individual values in the range I'm
going to go i t2 is equal to 0 and cycle
that guy off and then I can go even list
and then for each and then define that I
want to print out all of those values so
we can go n and print them so print line
and n so that's going to cycle through
and print all of those different guys
all those even values and we can run it
and see that anyway worked
all right so neat stuff alright so now I
would do something a little bit more
complex I want to call a function that
is going to return dynamically a created
function so outside of here I'm going to
call this guy
basically what this is going to return
to do is return a custom function that's
going to multiply values times the value
that's passed in so I'm going to go
function and I'm going to call this make
math function it's going to receive a
num and it's going to be an integer and
then it is going to return a function
that is going to multiply values times
then I'm 1 so what I do is I define that
this guy this function that is going to
be returned is going to receive an
integer and then what it's going to do
is return an integer and then I define
exactly what I want it to do so I'm
going to go num2 is like this and then
we're going to go norm 1 times num2
all right so it is a function that
generates functions pretty cool all
right so let's go and run it so I'm
going to go Val and let's say I want to
create a function that multiplies values
times 3 well I just call my make math
function and inside of this guy passed
the value of 3 and that's going to get
that inside of there and it's going to
create this custom function for me so of
course I have to make this B equals to
come down side here and then we can test
it to show that it indeed works fine so
I'm gonna go 5 times 3 is whoops times 3
is going to be equal to and I can have
this be multiplied 3 times 5 and run it
and you're going to say that 15 comes
back alright so that's a function that
creates functions now we're going to
create a nother one and what this is
going to do is it's going to receive a
list and a function to use on the list
so I'm going to go fun I'm going to call
this math on list num list and it's
going to receive an array and more
specifically an integer array and it's
also going to receive a function so this
is going to pass a function inside of a
function num and this is going to be an
integer
and we're defining what it does and this
function is going to return an integer
and then what I can do is go for Nam in
Nam lists for each of those values
passed inside of there I am going to
print out some information and for this
one I am going to say math on list just
so you can see what's going on there and
then I can refer to any function that is
passed inside of there as my funk and
numb on each of those items come back up
inside of here and call it so I'm going
to go value multiplied to is equal to
and I can go numb one integer and then I
can go numb one times two so there is
our function let's call this number one
there we are and then I'm going to go
Val num list 2 is equal to array of
let's go create and write four and five
and then I'm going to pass in both the
array as well as the function I want to
operate on there so a math on list and
we go numb list 2 and then multiply 2
and we can run it and up that I do I
didn't type in math on list that's okay
math on list that we are and run it and
it gave me another error
15 what's that air does it either that I
didn't make that uppercase I fixed it
now didn't I yes I did let's run it
again and you could see that it went and
multiplied two times each of those
values in the array all right so pretty
cool stuff in regards to higher-order
functions now I want to show you some
collection operators all right so these
collection operators are going to work
on any type of collection so rays and
you're going to see I'm going to cover
lists and maps and there's a couple
other different collections but either
way so let's say we wanted to sum all
the values in a list we go Val
and list sum is going to be equal to
number list 2 which is what I have right
there and I can call reduce to do just
that
and what I need to do with reduce is go
x and y and say that I want to sum those
values together you can form all sorts
of other different operations the fold
is kind of like reduce but it starts
with a initial value so I can come in
and grab this guy like that and I can do
hmm well let's also come in and print
this out so what did I do
let's go front line and reduce some and
then print out that list so we're going
to go list some and I'm going to do the
same thing with this guy so you can see
the difference between reduce as well as
fold so with fold what you're going to
do change us to list some to change this
to fold and fold is going to start off
with an initial value of 5 and then it
is going to continue adding all the
other values in the list to it so let's
change that to that and let's change
this to fold some so fold some and you
can run it and you can see that it is
indeed summing all of those values and
difference between it is to 10 and to 15
see see that reducing fold are very very
similar to each other we can come in and
check if any values are able to meet a
condition so let's say we wanted to do
something like evens and we wanted to
check if any of these values is even
well they can go numb list 2 followed by
an e and then have your condition to be
inside of there and we're going to be
able to use I T once again and 2 is
equal to 0 and you're going to be able
to get your answer from that guy let's
do a couple more of these you're like
wise well there's another one that is
all so in that situation the only
difference is is all of them are going
to have to be even to come back as true
in that situation you could also come in
here and return a list of values that
again meet a certain condition so let's
say we say Val big 3 is equal to num
list 2 and use filter for that and here
I'm just going to find my condition cell
greater than 3 and those are going to be
the ones that end up going inside of
that and let's go and print those out we
can go big 3.4 each and then let's go
and print all of them out put and print
line and here I'll just put greater than
3 you'll know what that means and print
all those values out let's run it see
what it looks like and there you can see
all those values come out and true and
false show up right there and for our
final example I want to show you map and
basically map is going to allow you to
perform an action on every single item
and then return a new list so here we go
Wow times 7 so I'm going to multiply
everything times 7 and we're going to do
that on our number list to call map and
then define exactly what I want to occur
in that situation so I'm going to take
each of those items and multiply them
times 2 and save them to a brand new
list and then we can say times 7 dot for
each and then print them all out so cool
stuff so print line and then we can go
like this and times 7 and print that is
all out thinking about that all right
yes it did and we can run it and when we
do you're going to see every item print
it out or multiply type 7 prints out
there we go there's a whole bunch of
different collection operators that are
available to you and now I want to talk
about exception handling and you all
know what exception handling is used for
it's handled or it allows us to handle
errors so that the programs do not crash
so I'm going to use the same type of
example I always use I'm going to have a
division by 0 so I'm going to have my
divisor be equal to 2 in this situation
and I'm going to do a division which
means there's a potential for division
by 0 to occur inside of here I'm going
to say
and the visor is equal to zero in that
situation I want to throw an exception
so I'm going to say a throw illegal
argument exception that is it and in
this situation we say can't divide by 0
else if there was no problem with that
literally doing here there's a little
problem here we get rid of that empanada
and throw it out there all right
now everything's ok else if that wasn't
a good one we can come in and we can say
get rid of that and we can say something
like 5 divided by and let's put our
divisor inside of there is equal to and
we will do our division inside here so 5
divided by divisor okay so everything's
fine now anytime we have a try block we
are going to try to catch our error and
in this situation when you go E oops
e and we are going to follow that up
with illegal argument exception of
course we're going to catch the exact
exception that we sent and then we are
going to or if you'd like to come in
here and print out the message that is
tied to that exception you can go e dot
message exactly like that and it will
print that out and we can run it and
since divisors - we have no problem but
if we come up here and change the
divisor to 0 and you're going to say
that it just goes and prints can't
divide by 0
all right so very very very brief
explanation of how exception handling
works inside of Kotlin but i think you
can catch on with the rest of it and now
i want to talk about some collections
and i'm going to start off with lists
now basically there are immutable lists
and there are mutable water refer to as
mutable lists alright so what I'm going
to do here at first is I want to create
a mutable list and then I'm going to
create an immutable list so we'll go var
call this list 1 and
this is immutable or a changeable list
mutate change get it alright so we're
going to go int and then I can go to
populate it I call mutable list of and 1
2 3 4 & 5 and there you go I just
created a mutable list if instead you
would like to create an immutable or a
list that does not change we're going to
come in here change this to Val instead
of our and we're going to change this to
list 2 and then this is going to just be
changed to a list so it's an integer
list and then we just come in here and
change this to a list of and let's just
copy or cut off that little part okay so
here is a mutable or changeable list
here is any immutable or unchangeable
list and that's how we create those now
I'm mainly going to be working with the
mutable list here let's say I want to
add an item to a mutable list I go list
1 and add and we can throw anything
inside of there that's how we add values
let's say I want to get our first item
don't want to do that let's go print
line and I want to get our first item
out of it I can do so and let's get this
and list 1 followed by first there that
is that's how to get that that's the
first item in the list let's say I want
to get the last item in the list well
guess what we type in last and like this
type in last like that and we can do a
whole bunch other things let's say we
want to get a value at a specific index
1 let's say we want it to be the second
index seconds and to do that we just go
to list 1 once again and let's just say
that change that to 2 how that operates
we can get a list starting from one
index to another so we're going to
create list 3 is equal to list 1 and we
call sub list and go from 0 to 3 and
that's going to create that that's how
to get a sub list we're also going to be
able to get the size of our
test call this length and we need to
call this list 1 and follow that up with
sighs yawns of course we're going to be
able to clear our list so let's go list
3 followed by clear it's going to get
rid of everything inside of the list we
can remove a value so we'll go to list
one followed by remove and let's say we
want to get rid of one we could also
remove at a specific index by saying
remove at and changing that to one and
we could add a value add an index so
it's Co hist one and let's say we want
it to be in the position of two and what
we want to add is 10 and of course we
can command and cycle through all of
these items inside of here by calling
for each and then after that let's get
rid of this sort her after that we can
go in and what we want done to each of
those items and here I'm going to say
print line and I'll go mutable list and
print out each of those items everything
looks ok I think so don't whoops I went
and hit enter right whenever I did that
all right on to that save it and run it
that the oops what we do to the there is
an error warning 13 what's going on with
13 I'll list who's never used that
that's not our main error let's get rid
of that so just for the heck of it look
over here and what do we have we have an
error on line 32 always ignore this and
this this is your specific application
your errors in 32 let's look at 32 oh I
see what I did I went there's um
actually no index 2 in this situation
let's just get rid of that all together
and we can save us and we can run it and
you can see right there it is going in
here grab the first value grab the last
or output of the last value the second
value was 3 the length was 6 then we
went and removed a whole bunch of
different things and you can see that it
printed out 4 and 6 for all of those
different items in
list okay so there's a whole bunch of
functions and ways to work with lists
and now I want to talk about maps
okay so a map is going to be a
modifiable collection that's going to
hold key valued pairs and let's go and
create an empty map so I'm going to go
map is equal to and of course there's
going to be immutable maps and immutable
maps or matted work with here is a
mutable map and how you load one is go
mutable map of and here I'm going to
define that the key is going to be an
integer and the value in this situation
is going to be anything and look like
this and there we go
so now we created our map now it's time
for us to use our map let's go
well I'm also going to show you how to
create a map in which you load values
whenever you first start it this is call
this map 2 is equal to mutable map and
mutable map of more specifically and
then in this guy what I'm going to do is
I'm going to say get rid of this and
have it figure it out I'm going to say
one two Doug and then I'm going to put
another element which is going to be two
to 25 okay so this is going to be the
key and this is going to be the value
that we are going to be working with
they can also add additional values
let's go map 1 and this is going to be 2
the guys doesn't have anything so I'm
going to throw Derek inside of there and
we go map and to again this is the key
and the value
I'll throw 42 inside of there I'm going
to be able to get the size of these
elements by just going let's call this
map size and then I will just have in
map size and map and size and there that
is we can also add a key value so we can
go map and put and say 3 and let's say
we want to put in Pittsburgh that is we
can also come in and remove a key and
value so we go map and we will use
remove and I'm going to remove whatever
is in the second key or whatever is
assigned to it and of course we're going
to be able to iterate
and get key values so I'll say four and
I'm going to say X and y and in math
pounds the X is going to be the key
otherwise is going to be the value and
we can go print line and just show that
I can say key and there's X and value
and so let's make the uppercase value
and Y alright and run it and you're
going to see that a map size 2 comes out
with this guy right here and here I
cycle through the different values and
printed them out the keys and values
okay so brief explanation of how maps
work in Kotlin now i want to talk about
classes all right so we're going to
create a class outside of the main
function right here and i can get rid of
this random function or there's random
and poor it up here because i'm not
going to use it anymore so we can come
down here like this and it's important
to understand up front of that there are
no static methods and that classes are
going to be marked as final like in java
by default unless they are marked as
open so i'm going to mark it as open
whoops go open there we go so open and
i'm going to create an animal class and
you're going to put the attributes you
want this guy to be set up with directly
thereafter
you're going to put the datatype you're
also let's say i want to have every
animal is going to have a name and a
height let's put that there and maybe it
makes more sense to put these on
multiple different lines and also you
can see I'm using Val here because this
is not going to change and bar here
because the height as well as the weight
could change so put that inside of there
and there is double okay and now let's
continue adding on to all the different
things I wish this wasn't quite so
verbose with all the squigglies
everywhere the drives me nuts
but he's okay basically your objects are
going to be initialized in an init
function and this is just going to be
where you're going to verify if a value
is okay or not so let's say let's also
talk about regular expressions here
very briefly like three lines of regular
expressions basically what I want to do
is I want to create a red X here that is
going to match for a number any place
inside of a string so let's say I want
to make it invalid to have a number
inside of an animal's name well how I
can define this regular expression is
like this and rig X and put this like
this and then what this is saying is
basically I'm checking to see if there
is a decimal value anywhere inside of
the string that's going to be assigned
to name and what I'm going to do is put
require inside here and basically what's
going to happen is if these requirements
aren't going to be met an illegal
argument exception is going to be thrown
so I talked about exception handling a
little bit ago so what I'm going to do
here is I'm going to say if name matches
any character inside of name matches for
the regular expression that we have up
here which means any of the characters
are numbers in that situation what I
want to do is I want to throw an error
so I'm going to say animal name can't
contain numbers all right
so that's going to be the message that
I'm going to shoot out let's go and do
them for other ones too so let's say
something like require and here I'm
going to say if height is greater than 0
what I'm doing is saying that height
must be greater than 0 and if it is not
the message I'm going to say is height
must be greater than 0 ok and let's do
the same thing and other requirements of
my class is that the weight of my
animals must also be greater than 0
otherwise I will not accept them as
valid animals and then inside of here
outside of an it of course I'm also
going to throw in a method and if you
want your assets your methods to be over
or provide for the option that your
message could be overridden you need to
put open here once again I'm going to
say fun and this is going to be called
get info and it's going to
output some information but it's not
going to return any information and what
it specifically is going to output let's
get this out of here is look and have
that there so we're going to say print
line and I'm going to get to the name
how you get the name value as you just
go dollar sign name is and here I'll
just say height and tall and weighs I'm
not going to get into specifics of what
type of that is we're using and there
you go so that's how you define the
attributes this is how you define what
is valid values for all of the different
attributes and this is how you define a
method for your class now what I want to
do is come up here after I have that set
up to come up inside of main and go and
create an animal object how you create
one is you go Bowser
like this is equal to and you do not
type new inside here you just type in
whatever it's called and then you want
to say Bowser or whatever the name is
and let's say I want a 20 point zero and
thirteen point five is valid and then I
can call for our function to execute I
go and get info exactly like that and
then we can run it as long as I'm having
errors yes Bowser is 20.0 tall and
weighs thirteen point five brief
explanation of how those all Walter
eight and now I'm going to talk about
inheritance okay so what we're going to
do is I'm going to create a new class
and I cut dog and it is going to inherit
since I don't have open on here you're
not going to be able to inherit from dog
I've decided so it's also going to
receive a name which is going to be a
string and it's also going to have a
height which is going to be a double and
it's going to have a weight which is
also going to be a double and it's also
going to have this time I have to put a
var it's going to have an owner whoops
owner like that and that's going to be a
string now to say that I want to inherit
from animal I just put a colon an animal
and then I let the name the height and
the weight the
initialized over inside of animal and
then it comes down like this and let's
say that I would like to override get
information I just go override fun get
info and of course I can put my own
methods inside of here do whatever I
want
this is not going to return anything and
let's just go and copy what this says so
it's just coffee that's change it up
slightly so name is height tall bla bla
bla bla bla and is owned by and owner
okay so there we go we just created a
dog which inherits a from animal and
it's come up here and test it to make
sure that it operates the way that we
feel that it should so I'm going to go
WOW spot is equal to and here I'm going
to call dog and spots and probably more
fizzles going to work in Kotlin just
like you would expect it to so it's like
this so I'm leave that for homework for
you to test out 14.5 and I'm Paul Smith
is the owner
I'm going to go spots and get info is
going to print that out and we're going
to run it and it should have worked
yeah spot is 20 inches tall weighs 14.5
and is owned by Paul smih okay so that's
how inheritance works inside of God well
now why don't I give a brief explanation
of how interfaces work all right so come
back down here inside here and what I'm
going to do is I am going to create an
interface so this is going to be an
interface that is going to provide for
the option to make something flyable and
an interface of course is just a
contract that states that all fields and
methods a class must implement if it
implements the interface so I'm going to
call this interface fly a bowl and I'm
going to say that anybody that is
basically wants to use the interface is
going to have to have a field inside of
it called flies and it is going to be a
boolean and it also is going to have a
fly method
Stud of its that is going to receive a
distance miles flown or whatever and
it's going to receive a double and it is
going to not do anything not return
anything all right and let's change and
let's look at that exactly the way we
have right there after this you know
what I'm going to create a bird class
that's going to implement that so I'm
going to go bird and you're going to be
able to call your constructor directly
from inside of here and do some like Val
and name and this is going to be a
string and I'm going to say right here
whoops the override VAR flies and to
implement the interface here what we're
going to do is follow the constructor
parameters with a colon and the
interface name oops let's also come in
here and make sure pull in and let's
give it a default value of true and then
I'm going to come in and go fly of all
fly oops
fly a hole it's getting late into this
tutorial
nothing up a little bit okay so there's
flyable and let's go and put this down
here so we can see more of this stuff
all at one time so there you can see it
all right so there's flyable and inside
of it we of course need to override the
function fly
so there's fly and this is going to be
distance miles and a double and of
course it's not going to return anything
and it's just down here because that's
confusing me pet hair and then what I'm
going to do is I'm going to say if flies
in that situation I want to print out
that whatever the name of our bird is is
going to fly a certain number of
distance miles and then I'll say miles
after that and there that is and did I
do this right I think it did there's
liable there's that there's this
everything looks good and then we'll
come up inside of here and test out our
interface
so there's all this stuff that we are
we're in the main function and I'm going
to create a bird let's call it Tweety so
is equal to bird and the name is Tweety
and it is going to be true that Tweety
is a flying bird and then we can say
tweet and call for the fly function to
work and we'll say that Tweety flew 10
miles let's run that and see if I have
any errors
oops have an error what do we got
unresolved reference tweet distance
miles
ok so 17 Oh Tweety spell that let's run
it again just see that to the anyway
another air 62 unresolved reference
distance miles distance miles just just
miles all this miles let's change this
the distance miles right there the
distance miles right there Oh so should
be okay I'm just going to run it and do
and you can see Tweety flies 10 miles ok
so there you go there's interfaces and a
whole bunch of other different things
and to finish off everything I'm going
to talk about null safety
okay so null safety is built directly
into Kotlin because there's it's null
causes lots of issues so causing that's
one thing that cousin tries to do is is
to solve potential issues now to by
default you actually cannot assign null
and I'm going to show you this I'm going
to null value like this and string is
equal to null ok you're going to see
that it gives me an error and what it
says is null cannot be a value of a non
null type string ok so you can't do that
however you can allow for a null value
to be assigned and how you do that is
you just put a question mark inside
there and there you can see that the
error went away now another thing is a
function may return null and in the
situation which that occurs you're also
going to be used our little question
mark so let's go fun and my fun for
function and
ring so if there's a chance that this
could return a null value you are going
to put the little question mark there
let's go and actually do a real-world
example here instead of just doing
something a little bit weird so we're
going to have fun and this guy is
actually going to return all the time so
we're going to go turn null and we will
put string inside of here like this and
create a function and the whole purpose
of this function is to return null -
cause you know issues and so forth you
can see right there I did it and it did
not give me any errors another thing
that is neat is that Kotlin is going to
provide for the opportunity of a null
value if an if statement is going to
protect it from danger so what we're
going to do here is I'm going to go var
and know Val 2 is equal to return null
so we're going to call that function
that sole purpose is to return the null
value and then what I'm going to do down
here is I'm going to use what Kotlin
refers to as a smart cast so I'm going
to say if no Val 2 is not equal to null
in that situation I am going to go in
here and try to print it out or print
out length of that so I'm going to say
no Val - dot link and there that is now
if I didn't have this here this would be
throwing an error but since I do have
that if statements there like I said
it's called a smart cast and Kotlin
smart enough to allow me to do that
since I caught the null issue myself you
could also use the Force operator to
force an all assignment so in this way
we go in all Val 3 is equal to null Val
- and then you put - that's the force
operator - exclamation marks and lengths
like that and it's going to provide for
the option and then the final thing is
you can use the Elvis operator to assign
a default value if the value could be
not so and how that would work is you
would go for
all for this is a string and in this
situation we're going to call the old
return null which only exists to return
null and there is the Elvis operator
it's going to be a question mark
followed by a colon and there will say
if you try to assign a value of null
tune all Val for instead install or
assign the value of no name okay so
there you go guys
did my best to cover the vast majority
of what you're going to need to get
going in regards to working with a
absolutely super awesome language Kotlin
and if you guys have any questions or
comments please leave them down below
otherwise till next time